Joy Kwamboka

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

kwambokaj2.jk@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +254711607261

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Web developer, an avid Open-Source enthusiast with adept collaborative skills and a strong understanding of web design. Well-versed in front and back-end development languages, frameworks, and libraries to optimize the user experience.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication, Problem Solving, Work Ethic

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

January 2022 - Present

As a remote full-stack developer, I have worked on more than 20 projects using programming languages such as JavaScript, React-Redux, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML and CSS. Below are some of my work:

Yacht House App - This application allows a user to reserve a house at the beach or in the ocean. The admin also has the privilege of adding and removing a house.

- Built with: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React-Redux, CSS3, Heroku, Git version control, GitHub
- Repository link: <u>Source Code</u>
- Demo link: Video Demonstration

Beauty Parlour App - This application displays various makeup products from different brands. The user is able to select a brand, view the products entailed in the brand and the description and price of the product.

- Built with: React-Redux, CSS3, Git version control, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify
- Repository link: <u>Source Code</u>
- Demo link: Video Demonstration

Restaurant App — The website displays different meal categories; one can like or comment on the specific category.

- Built with: Vanilla JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Git version control, GitHub
- Repository link: Source Code
- Demo link: Video Demonstration

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

April 2022 - October 2022

- Mentored 2 junior web developers monthly on a 1:1 basis, providing technical support through 10+ code reviews weekly.
- Proposed improvements to code organisation to improve code quality and overall performance by 10% in the quarter of work.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program, enhancing student retention by 5% from the previous year.

STATE DEPARTMENT OF LIVESTOCK

Nairobi, Kenya

Secretariat

January 2020 - March 2022

• Developed a WordPress website that increased awareness of the government project by 50% and successfully engaged 3 more investors to sponsor the project development.

• Gathered and prepared crucial information concerning the livestock sector in my country. This improved the decision-making process by 80%.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE March 2022 – October, 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

TAITA TAVETA UNIVERSITY

September 2015 - April 2019

BSc in Mathematics and Computer Science; major in Statistics

• Spent 4 years learning computer Systems and Security, and programming languages, among others.